ILGWU Justice Photographs 5780/102 P
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
- Mondale - Ferraro (Box 21, Folder 5)
  Includes: negatives of Mondale/Ferraro Rally- with Mario Cuomo, Sol Chaikin, Ed Koch, Ferraro, and Mondale speaking; Portrait of Sol Chaikin, Evelyn Dubrow speaking- negative
- Political Action (Box 21, Folder 6)
  Includes: JFK at Garment Center Rally; JFK speaking- 1960; VP Lou Montenegro- Midwest Regional Director questions former Illinois Senator Adlai Stevenson- 5/82; Senator Kennedy greets ILGWU activist- 5/82; Mario Cuomo raises hand to crowd- 7/82; ILGWU Retirees with Congressman Claude Pepper; photo of Mayor Andrew Young; LA Mayor Tom Bradley photo-9/82; Adlai Stevenson, VP Lou Montenegro, Auggie Salas- president of Hispanic American Labor Council, and Jessie Rios, HALC secretary- 10.82; Howard Metzenbaum photo; Governor Jerry Brown- CA; at ILG legislative action conference reception in Washington 5/6/83- Fred Siems, ILG VP, Senator Henry Jackson, Congressman Solarz, Sol Chaikin and Mrs. Chaikin; rally for Mondale/Ferraro- 11/11/84; Chaikin speaks to rally
- Political Action (Box 21, Folder 7)
  Includes: Robert Morgenthau with Chairlady Elizabeth Vass and NY Dress Joint Board Business Agent Shirley Rose at Varpej Couture- 9/15/74; Hugh Carey of NY is greeted by Manager Mike Primack of Eastern Region Local 154- 11/15/74; Manager Joseph Longo of Dressmakers Boro Park Office urges support for Leo Zeferetti with Assistant Manager Nick Bonaserra and Manager Sal Cubisino of Local 48, Assistant Manager William Weiss of Local 10, VP Ed Schneider- manager of Local 91 9/1/76; Dan Moynihan discusses need for tax reform at Rally of Local 57-77 with David Wells, ILGWU Assistant Political Director, Louis Sepe- president of Local 57-77, Manager of 57-77 Richard Cerbone; Sol Goldberg- 11/1/76; Senator Harrison Williams chats with ILGers at Schuetzen Park, North Bergen- 10/23/76; Jimmy Carter speaks at Scheutzen Park with VP Ed Kramer, Eastern Region general manager, Senator Harrison Williams- 11/1/76; Chaikin with Senator Byrd of West Virginia; Barney Frank with New England Region Associate Director Ron Alman and VP Edward Milano- 10/80; ILGers Katherine Campbell and Louise Winant visited Rep. Matthew McHugh- 12/80; Walter Mondale at Local 120's rally in Decatur, IL with Mary Kincaid- 12/80; Mondale with S. Bianco and Ray Must; Midwest Region Director VP Lou Montenegro heads locals at rally 10/6/80- pictured ILGWU banner; photos of ILGWU rally supporting Carter 12/80; Carter addresses Garment Center Rally- 10/30/80; Moynihan testifies at a hearing- 6/2/81; Sol Chaikin announces support of Mario Cuomo 3/8/82- with General Secretary-Treasurer Shelley Appleton, VP Wilbur Daniels; Congressman James Florio of NJ- 1981; Benjamin Robbs, Howard Hoagland, Laurel Martino, Charles Dougherty, Lois Reed, Bernard Gibbs, Paul Arrington; Laurel Martino; Lois Reed, William Gray III, Daisy Wilford, Elmer Pratt, Paul Arrington, Ben Robbs; NY Mayor Ed Koch addresses ILGWU Council of Managers with Shelley Appleton, Chaikin, and Wilbur Daniels- 9/81
- Price Settlement (Box 21, Folder 8)
  Includes: talks at Abe Schrader store 1959
- Promotions (Box 21, Folder 9)
  Includes: Members of the ILGWU retirees club sewing banner that hung in Balto Museum of Art; photo of woman getting hair done for ILGWU scene; two women posing for camera for scene; Union Label Chorus singing at a delegate convention; union label chorus practicing; photos of preparations for taping an ILGWU scene; a portrait of the Barbee's; Sol Chaikin congratulates 1977 winners of ILGWU design competition with Wilbur Daniels and June Weir- fashion editor of women's wear; winner Kevin Emard with Chaikin and VP Daniels; winner Kevin Emard speaking; Chaikin and wife Rosalind with VP Daniels, Sandhaus- executive director NY Coast and Suit Association; Chaikin poses with all the winners; designer Kasper, NY Daily News Fashion Editor Kathy Larkin with two of the judges, and students Rebecca Moses, Stephen Leavitt, Sherwin Derby, and Jan Carter
- Promotions (Box 21, Folder 10)
- Promotion, Black and white photograph; Color photograph (Box 21, Folder 11)
- Promotions (Box 21, Folder 12)
  Includes: little girls being directed for union label scene- 2/76; VP Wilbur Daniels and Bernard Waldman- coordinator of the ILGWU sponsored "Next Great Designer" contest examine entries- 12/15/75; Kathy Larkin arranges entries for contest- 3/1/76; designer Bill Blass looks at sketches for contest; designer Calvin Kelan finds appealing sketches in contest; Donna Karan of Anne Klein looks at sketches; VP Julius Ramirez- manager Local 32 introduces Alicia Vidal of Brooklyn- 5/15/76; VP Philip Milner and VP Frank Wright, ILGWU VP Wilburn Daniels, Dottie O'Neill, Julie Ballantyne, bank manager Joe Pollicino, and ILGWU VP Murray Gross- NY Dress Joint Board general manager at opening of exhibit showing the winning sketches- 8/1/76; Wilbur Daniels- ILGWU VP views designs- 3/1/77; union label message that appears on NYC buses- 12/15/76; Jim Prine, cutter at Nelly Don Shop in Nevada, Missouri and member of Local 419 does a commercial-11/1/76; Norma Roethemeir is interviewed by Dwight Burton- as director Nat Eisenberg looks on- 3/31/78
- Promotions (Box 21, Folder 13)
  Includes: Mayor Shunichi Suzuki of Tokyo and his wife are welcomed by Chaikin and his wife with Ed Koch; President Chaikin answers a question by Judy Licht; VP Evelyn Dubrow with President Wilbur Daniels and Mrs. Mondale; models at the show- 6/80; workers at Dalma Dress Shop in NYC area filmed for a TV show- 7/86; members signing "Look for the Union Label" for TV on corner of 39th Street and Eighth Avenue- 7/80; Rhoda Bates interviews VP Jay Mazur- Local 23-25 manager and Local 22 Administrative Supervisor Israel Berkenworld and Asst. President Gus Tyler- 7/80
- Puerto Rico (Box 21, Folder 14)
  Includes: Sol Chaikin greets Puerto Rico's first lady with VP Clifford Depin- Puerto Rico regional director looking on; Cristina Diaz, Puerto Rican artist presents a painting to Chaikin with VP Depin, Local 600 officers- Candida Osorio- VP Neredia Colon- Secretary, Hilda Maldondo- treasurer, Coranda Martinez- president and Local 601 Lillian Clinton, Lida Colon, Santa Rios; Eddie Franticelli, Ellis Rosenthal, Jack Delman of Splendor Form, Attorney Melvin Kleebatt, Chaikin, VP Depin, Jack Gross, Louis Rolnick, Maria Serrano, Leona Vanterpool, William Schulman, and Fernando Cortes at trustees meeting at Cerromar Beach Hotel; union negotiating team meetings with ers- 2/1/76; workers of Caribe Harbor, a Jonathon Logan subsidiary in Arroyo, Puerto Rico wave bankruptcy checks- 2/15/75; Gloria Velazquez does as Regional Director Clifford Depin, Chairlady Isolina Soto, plant manager Eddie Fraticelli look on at Margot Manufacturing in Arecibo, PR- 9/1/75; Regional Director Clifford Depin drops by Gloria Velazquez home to check on her son with chairlady is Olina Soto- 9/1/75; PR locals 600-601 gathered in the Ponce Area for a seminar with Eddie Fraticelli, Santiago Paz, Depin, Jesus Ferrer, Dr. Mario Sanchez Solis, Mrs. Hilda Coimbre, Dr. Victor Rosario- 10/1/75; Chaikin, Nathan Katz, Jack Gross, VP Depin, Leono Vanterpool, Maria Serrano, Louis Relnick, William Schulman, and Fernando Cortez at a meeting for Local 600-601 members show books of speeches distributed- Nida de Jesus, Rosa Cecilia, Andrea Rivera, Aurelia Colon, Maria Moreno, and Martiza Rivera- 4/15/76; PR governor, and Ms. Raphael Hernandez Colon with Dan Moynihan at a dinner- 10/1/76; Mercedes Diaz- head of Puerto Rico retiree group, explains club activities to new members- 2/15/77; Charles S. Zimmerman presents L.I.D. "1957 Annual Award" for Louis Munoz Marin- governor of PR to Signor Fernando Sierra Berdecia- in center is Chester Bowles, Ambassador to India Nathan Minkoff and Harry Laidler- 4/13/57
- Retirees (Box 21, Folder 15)
  Includes: President Louis Stulberg addresses ILGWU retirees at Avery Fisher Hall in NY's Lincoln Center- 11/1/75; meeting of the Senior Club of NY local 22- 8/21/74- Rosina Prescott, Abe Rosheo, Israel Breslow, Emanuel Gonzalez, Rose Breslow, Natalie Vasquez, Sandra Gelman, Zalman J. Lichtenstein, Ida Gluck and Mildred Weiler; ILGWU retirees go backstage at Roundabout Theater in Manhattan- Mary Goff Schuster, Priscella Timpson with performers Michele Shay, Dick Shawn, and Carol Teitel, and retirees Bella Hyman and Max Schwartz- 8/1/76; Congressman Al Ullman chairman of House Ways and Means Committee addresses luncheon of Golden Ring Council Senior Citizens 10/12/76- Chaikin, VP Wilbur Daniels, VP Howard Molisani, VP David Gingold, Dr. Virginia Trotter of HEW, former HEW Secretary Wilbur Cohen, former Social Security Commissioner Robert Ball and Congressman James Burke; Sol Chaikin congratulates the members of the ILGWU Retiree Service Department on the 10th Anniversary- with DP and VP Wilburn Daniels, and VP David Gingold- 2/15/77; signing of a petition at shop in Kingston NY 9/80; Saul Wolfson- social security administration speaking 12/83; Nassau County retirees dancing at a Christmas party at Theresa's Restaurant in North Massapequa, NY- 2/83; April 10, 1985 rally- retirees carry placards with names of shops that closed because of imports- 5/85; Comb. Valley Retirees Club
- Retirement Fund (Box 21, Folder 16)
  Includes: President Louis Stulberg urge improvement in retirees benefits at a board meeting- 12/15/74; meeting of Board of Trustees of ILGWU Retirement Fund- Chaikin, Samuel Sandhaus, Henoch Mendelsund, Wilbur Daniels, Howard Molisani; meeting of ILGWU National Retirement fund meeting with Louis Rolnick speaking and Sol Chaikin- 1/1/77; Sol Chaikin presides as ILGWU National Retirement Fund meeting of trustees- Nelson Cruikshank, Daniels, Consul Theodore Bernstein, Louis Rolnick, Auditor William Schulman, and Jack Elkin- 12/1/75
- Safety and Health (Box 21, Folder 17)
  Includes: Chaikin speaking to a wellness class; pictures of an exercise class; Assistant President Gus Tyler and President Wilbur Daniels at Triangle Fire ceremony; Executive VP Fred Seems, Alice Tse, Jay Mazur, and Shelley Appleton present wreath at fire sit- 4/83; members leaning appropriate extinguisher for combustible solid and other fires; Frank Lombardo (Local 89-48) and Joe Longo (Local 22) check on Carbon Monoxide levels of a cigarette burning; VP Frederick R. Siems addresses institute participants; participants listen to comment by Debra Jakubic; other photos of participants in the institute- 3/83; photo of a worker with poor posture- 2/81; operator demonstrates proper sitting position- 2/81; photo of cleaning fluids
- Safety and Health (Box 21, Folder 18)
  Includes: Susan Law discusses dyeing room conditions with ILGWU engineer Raphael Kalmenoff 5/82; shield protects workers' faces and upper body; machine guards protect operators fingers; shop chairperson Carlos Rodriguez at a polishing wheel-10/82; woman sewing on a machine with a needle guard; Mottern shows Law accident and incident reports; Susan Lau with Paul Mottern, committee chairperson, showing her exit routes- 3/82; woman demonstrating vacuum hose in order to remove lint before you leave the shop; Susan Law, project coordinator for the Health and Safety Department addresses eighty Kentucky executive board members during an education conference; photo of a fire extinguisher- 1/82; Dr. Rose Goldman, Janet Prayzner, and Dr. Anna Radovsky- 2/83; Members of Local 178, Fall River, Massachusetts in a dance class- 2/83; Gail Wholl- program coordinator of Health and Safety Department, Frank Pereira- assistant manager New England District, Manager Nicholas Raissos, Aaron Mittleman, president of New England District, Joe Danahy, assistant director of organization and field services and business agent Jim Desmarais at a seminar for employers- 2/83; Harvard University researcher Laura Punnett speaks with ILGer at Dalmar Dress in NYC- 1/83; Management Engineering Director Mitchell Lokiec explains machine operation to Dr. Monroe Keyserling- 1/83
- Scott Singer (Box 21, Folder 19)
  Includes: slides
- Shop Scenes- Women Sewing - digital photos (Box 21, Folder 20)
  Includes: individual operators, black women sewings, hands at a sewing machine
- Shop Scenes - Women Sewing (Box 22, Folder 1)
  Includes: individual operators hands manually sewing, woman threading needle, hands and sewing machine
- Shop Scenes - Pressers (Box 22, Folder 2)
  Includes: individual operators at press machines, black man at press machines
- Shop Scenes - Cutters digital photos (Box 22, Folder 3)
  Includes: individual operating cutting machines or measuring, hands measuring for a cut
- Shop Scenes - Historical (Box 22, Folder 4)
  Includes: portrait of woman sewing, shop scene of sewing men workers, ladies gathered around a sewing machine with shop lady, early 1900's photo of male at sewing machine; first dress shop sit-down strike- 4/11/35 in a NYC Dress Shop- people idle at their machines, early ally scene with boxed garments, four women hand sewing, a portrait of families living in destitute conditions, negative of children working at a sewing machine
- Shop Scenes (Box 22, Folder 5)
  Includes: A man picking up a bundle of cloth
- Shop Scenes (Box 22, Folder 6)
  Includes: man writing labels/tags out
- Shop Scenes (Box 22, Folder 7)
  Includes: Hispanic man carrying package, man pushing packages through snow, young Hispanic men/boys rest while carrying packages
- Shop Scenes (Box 22, Folder 8)
  Includes: a tailor checks fitting of neon finished garments on dummies in Jonathon Logan Plant women tucking in garments on a dummy, woman standing by her dress
- Shop Scenes digital photos (Box 22, Folder 9)
  Includes: male carrying finished clothes to a store, man pushing a rack of clothes to a store, man attaching labels to a rack of clothes, black man pushing rack of clothes and one carrying a garment bag
- Shop Scenes (Box 22, Folder 10)
  Includes: topless man pushing hand truck, man at presser- very hot outside
- Shop Scenes (Box 22, Folder 11)
  Includes: black men pushing/maneuvering a rack of garments, shop scenes of women sewing, Hispanic man resting on rolled up cloth, shop scenes of men sewing, spools of thread factory scene shop scene demonstration
- Shop Scenes (Box 22, Folder 12)
  Includes: man at pressing machine, shop scenes of women sewing, men delivering packages, sorting records in Record Room of Health Center, men delivering racks of garments, fabric factory shop scene, photo of finished garments and pre-processed cloth
- Shop Scenes digital photos (Box 22, Folder 13)
  Includes: shop scenes of women working on sewing machines, shop scenes of fabric factory, men delivering cloth
- Shop Scene (Box 22, Folder 14)
  Includes: contact sheets
- Shop Scene (Box 22, Folder 15)
- Shop Scene (Box 22, Folder 16)
  Includes: late 50's-60's- black woman labeling clothes, individual operators, man moving cloth, portrait of hand-sewing, manager looks over two women cutting thread as a part of a "Time Motion Study", men looking over sketches of designs, black woman putting finishing touches on a garment, hands by a sewing machine
- Shop Scenes (Box 22, Folder 17)
  Includes: late 50's-60's- Asian woman cutting cloth, woman and black man taking in cloth on a dummy, women hand sewing, individual operators, woman packaging thread
- Shop Scenes (Box 22, Folder 18)
  Includes: portraits of Government workers late seventies- 1980, workers of bridal store- Gina Bridals- individual operators
- Shop Scenes (Box 22, Folder 19)
  Includes: mid-sixties- early seventies- man carrying rolls of cloth, women put finishing touches on garments, individual operators, women sorting fabric, women hand sewing
- Shop Scenes (Box 22, Folder 20)
  Includes: mid sixties- early seventies workers raising hands at a meeting, woman shows off her finished dress, individual operators, man unraveling cloth, black man fitting a dummy with cloth, man making models for dummy
- Shop Scenes (Box 22, Folder 21)
  Includes: individual operators, woman at pinking machine, Korean tot Marce Park holds a union label doll, tail ends of cloth, speaker at the Philadelphia Dress Joint Board conference members filling out cards
- Shop Scenes - Cutters (Box 22, Folder 22)
  Includes: individual operators, shop scenes of men cutting, photo of hands cutting
- Shop Scenes Cutters - Old digital photos (Box 22, Folder 23)
  Includes: individual operators, men in awkward positions cutting, stretching the cloth before cutting, spreading cloth before cutting, hands cutting, men cutting layers of fabric at once, cutters in shorts because it's hot
- Shop Scenes (Box 22, Folder 24)
  Includes: men sitting on bundles
- Shop Scenes - Sewing Hands (Box 22, Folder 25)
  Includes: sewing hands (see Box 3 folder 35-38)
- Shop Scenes - Women Sewing Coats in Shop (Box 22, Folder 26)
  Includes: women sewing coats in factory
- Shop Scenes. - "Man in Cutting Shop." (Box 22, Folder 27)
- Shop Scenes - Operator (Box 22, Folder 28)
  Includes: man operating a machine
- Shop Scenes - "Woman Sewing" (Box 22, Folder 29)
  Includes: individual and shop scenes, hands sewing
- Shop Scenes - "Woman Sewing by Hand." (Box 22, Folder 30)
  Includes: woman sewing with an ace bandage on arm
- Shop Scenes - "Markers". (Box 22, Folder 31)
  Includes: men marking clothes
- Shop Scenes - "Hands and Sewing Machine". (Box 22, Folder 32)
  Includes: just hands sewing- black and white women on machines
- Shop Scenes - "Operators" (Box 22, Folder 33)
  Includes: black woman operators
- Shop Scenes - "Presser". (Box 22, Folder 34)
  Includes: male presser
- Shop Scenes - "Woman Sewing By Hand". (Box 22, Folder 35)
  Includes: woman with Ace bandage sewing
- Shop Scenes - "Man Pressing Apparel". (Box 22, Folder 36)
  Includes: man in tank top sweating pressing apparel
- Shop Scenes - "Pressing Setting". (Box 22, Folder 37)
- Shop Scenes - "Profile of Women Sewing" (Box 23, Folder 1)
- Shop Scenes: digital photos (Box 23, Folder 2)
  Includes: individual operators sewing, woman sewing with a child looking on, women sewing at home- August 1980, interview rep others at the door of a sweatshop in 70's-80's; sweatshop-1970; Federation of Apparel Manufacturers- Kurt Barnard, Manny Eagle, Eugene Steinberg, Yale Garber, and Sam Butler; Rep. Philip Burton, Pat Williams, George Miller, Millicent Fenwick, Marge Roukema
- Shop Scenes - Industrial Scenes (Box 23, Folder 3)
  Includes: Earl Byrd at his machine; Hispanic man drawing- Jose O'Campo; Rocky Fosco writing labels; Pepe Venduzio; Iva McWilliams at her machine; black woman Paola Roman, Hispanic, at her press; shop scenes at Maidenform; individual operators
- Shop Scenes - Industrial Scenes (Box 23, Folder 4)
  Includes: cutting room photo, individual operators sewing, hands sewing, man unrolling cloth
- Shop Scenes - Operator (Box 23, Folder 5)
  Includes: individual operators sewing, shop scene of women sewing
- Shop Scenes - Operator (Box 23, Folder 6)
  Includes: man sewing
- Shop Scenes - Women Sewing (Box 23, Folder 7)
  Includes: shop scenes of women sewing
- Shop Scenes - Older Shop Photos - digital photos (Box 23, Folder 8)
  Includes: individual operators sewing, men cutting, shop scenes women sewing, Asian women sewing, black women at ILGWU event, black woman handing out leaflets, men pressing
- Shop Scene - "Sewing Buttons". (Box 23, Folder 9)
  Includes: women sewing buttons
- Shop Scene - "Women Sewing". (Box 23, Folder 10)
  Includes: shop scenes
- Southeast Region (Box 23, Folder 11)
  Includes: Beatrice Cox, Wylene Blanton, Sally Pearson, Shirley Baily, Joyce Crews, and Joyce Music celebrate with a backpay check- 8/15/74; Local 415-475 in Miami, Florida hoist a banner while boarding a plane to Mexico- 8/1/574; Victoria Armeteros, Ana M. Debesa, Esther Hernandez, and Alicia Marquez, Gloria Dopico, Gloria Alvarez, Nilda Lima, Adela Ortiz with backpay check from a strike- 9/1/74; Harry Berger- Southeast Region Assistant Director, Business Agent Claudette Taylor, Frances Solomon, Frances Sargent, VP Nicholas Bonanno, Willie Chisolm meet Governor George Busbee- 11/1574; Sol Chaikin addresses Southeast Region conference Orlando Beach, FL- 8/15/77; Upper South Department holds a banner in a parade; Southeast Region conference- Nicholas Bonanno, Chaikin, and others speak
- Southeast Region (Box 23, Folder 12)
  Includes: Georgia Congressman Elliot Levitas speaks at Southeast Region conference- 8/15/75; Simon Mogilner plants signing of first contract in Birmingham, Alabama- with Helen Anderson, Janice Barnes, Dale Abbott, Birdie Forbes, Joyce Wood, Doyle Simmons, Bill Porter, Martha Hudson, Faye Campbell, and Zelna Blakney- 3/1/75; ILGers picket outside Character Foundations in Dania, Florida- 4/15/75; Tilda Hood, Armanda Hood of Local 527, and State Director Benny Dansauage tend the ILGWU exhibit at Spirit of Labor Festival in Birmingham, AL- 1/1/76; Gustavo Rodriguez receives backpay check from Miami Manager Mayer Finkel while Juan Lozano looks on- 7/1/76; VP Nicholas Bonanno and Minnesota AFL-CIO President David Rowe at Kiryat- Segal-Efal, Tel Aviv- 9/1/76; conference at Desoto Hilton; Sol Chaikin addresses Miami retirees while VP Nicholas Bonanno, Wilbur Daniels, Matthew Schoenwald look on- with Max Brown- 3/15/77
- Southeast Region (Box 23, Folder 13)
  Includes: conference of AFL-CIO committee on Political Education in Jacksonville, FL- 2/7/70; workers at Stevens Fashions in Carrolton, AL receive charter from Morton Shapiro- asst. director of Southeast Region; striking members from Selma, AL march in funeral procession of Dr. Martin Luther King, Jr.; Martin Luther King, Sr. father of Martin Luther King, Jr. receives lunch from Southeast Region staffer Leona Craig in Atlanta- 9/19/70; 25 year members of Local 457 receive pins in Cullman, AL- 12/15/70; General Secretary-Treasurer Jay Mazur, Dimas Rodriguez- Local 415-475 VP, Fanny Pepper- President, Miguel Ruano- manager, VP Nicholas Bonanno attend a Local 415-475 meeting- Nov. 1983; James C. Davis receives a "cold welcome" in Atlanta; Organizer Edward Sharp presents check to Bernice Hutto and Levon Wallace from Moulton Mfg. Co. in Moulton, AL for backpay
- Southeast Region (Box 23, Folder 14)